<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An excellent new song, called, The gentlemans resolution. For a pleasant country life.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B03184</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3820</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.39.k.6[39]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99887419</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99887419</idno>
            <idno type="VID">182125</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B03184)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 182125)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; A3:1[39])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An excellent new song, called, The gentlemans resolution. For a pleasant country life.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.) : music.  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Charles Barnet.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place and date of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Verse: "Come, come, come, come, ... let us leave ..."</note>
                  <note>Printed in two columns.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ballads, English --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="song">
            <pb facs="tcp:182125:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <head>An excellent New SONG, Called, The Gentlemans Reſolution. FOR <hi>A Pleaſant Country Life.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <gap reason="music">
                  <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="music">
                  <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="music">
                  <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="music">
                  <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="music">
                  <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>I.</head>
               <l>COme, come, come, come, ... let us leave, ..</l>
               <l>Let us, let us leave the Town, come, come, come, come,</l>
               <l>Come, come, come, come, let us leave, ..</l>
               <l>Let us, let us, let us leave the Town, &amp; in ſome lovly place</l>
               <l>Where Crouds and Noiſe, where Crouds and Noiſe</l>
               <l>Were never, never, never, never known,</l>
               <l>Re-ſol—ve to ſpend our days,</l>
               <l>In pleaſant, pleaſant Sha—des,</l>
               <l>In pleaſant, pleaſant Shades upon the Graſs</l>
               <l>At Night our ſelves we'll lay,</l>
               <l>Our days in harmleſs ſports ſhall paſs,</l>
               <l>Our days in harmleſs ſports, in harmleſs ſports ſhall paſs,</l>
               <l>Thus time ſhall ſli—de away.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>II.</head>
               <l>Call, call, call, call, ... call the Coach, ..</l>
               <l>Call the, call the Coach away, call, call, call, call,</l>
               <l>Call, call, call, call, .. call the Coach, ..</l>
               <l>Call the, call the, call the Coach away, &amp; let us go in time</l>
               <l>To Woods and Groves, to Woods and Groves,</l>
               <l>Let's hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, ſtraight,</l>
               <l>Where Charm—ing Birds do Sing,</l>
               <l>Their Tuneful, Tuneful No—tes,</l>
               <l>Their Tuneful, Tuneful Notes does ſound each day,</l>
               <l>There let us on the Ground</l>
               <l>Within each others Arms to lye,</l>
               <l>Within each others Arms, each others Arms to lye,</l>
               <l>And tumble o—n the Ground.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>III.</head>
               <l>What, what, what, what, .. is there in, ..</l>
               <l>Is there, is therein this Town, what what what what?</l>
               <l>What, what, what, what, .. is there in, ..</l>
               <l>Is there, is there, is there in this Town but lewd Debauchery</l>
               <l>We Drink all night, we Drink all night,</l>
               <l>And tipple, tipple, tipple, tipple on,</l>
               <l>Till Bot—tles fly about,</l>
               <l>Then Whinnyard, Whinnyard's dra—wn,</l>
               <l>Then whinnyard, whinnyard's drawn &amp; one's ran thro'</l>
               <l>This is the Trade o'th' Town.</l>
               <l>Then let's a Country life all live,</l>
               <l>Then let's a Country life, a Country life all live</l>
               <l>Where Lewdneſs i—s not known.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>IV.</head>
               <l>Come, come, come, come, ... let us go, ..</l>
               <l>Let us, let us go with ſpeed, come, come, come, come, ...</l>
               <l>Come, come, come, come, let us go, ..</l>
               <l>Let us, let us, let us go with ſpeed &amp; leave this naſty Town</l>
               <l>For wine and Punk, for wine and Punk,</l>
               <l>Does ever, ever, ever, ever make</l>
               <l>Us Ma—d by being Drunk,</l>
               <l>Then follow, follow Boy—s,</l>
               <l>Then follow, follow Boys, let's goe while ſound</l>
               <l>To Pleaſure Night and Day,</l>
               <l>Where freſh young Country Maids are found,</l>
               <l>Where freſh young Country Maids, young Country Mai<gap reason="illegible: page cropped" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> are ſound</l>
               <l>To paſs the ti—me away.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for <hi>Charles Barnet.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
